The New Morning Water released the presence, the power and the glory of Jesus Christ
into the lives of all who received even just a drop of it.
Demonic beings, hidden sicknesses and the plan of the devil against the lives of so many people
were broken and cast out in the name of Jesus Christ.
A glorious liberty began to replace years of oppression and bondage.
Holy relaxation replaced the years of tension and pressure God's people had endured through the ministration.
Watch the mighty deliverance of this woman through the New Morning Water.
Holy Ghost fire all over her body !
Fire, in the mighty name of Jesus Christ !
Now, speak out! Who are you ?
Who are you ? Speak out !
She came to me because she wanted to give birth.
That's why I entered her - she had to give birth. I entered her through her culture.
She begged me. She said, "I want to give birth. Please, have mercy on me".
Who are you ?
She has to slaughter a goat.
I am the spirit from the mother.
You evil spirit !
You can't destroy me.
Listen!
I have destroyed her family; the family is useless.
Now listen to me, you evil spirits!
All of them are useless.
What are the bad habits?
She has nothing now; she is a drunkard.
She is my wife; she is my woman - I made her useless.
What are the bad habits you have given her?
She is my woman.
She drinks and she smokes.
Anytime she drinks what happens to her ?
Even if you go to her hotel now, there is more - she bought more.
She is my woman; you can't take her from me.
She begged me.
Listen, in Jesus' name! Any time she smokes and drinks, what happens to her ?
What happens when she starts drinking and smoking ?
She goes crazy; she drives - she wouldn't know where she is going.
She always drives.
You spirit of drunkenness, what else have you caused this woman to do ?
What else ? Speak out !
What else have you caused her to do in her life ?
Speak out! Fire all over your body, in the mighty name of Jesus Christ !
Spirit of drunkenness, what else have you caused her ?
What else ? Speak out!
She smokes - she can smoke 20 boxes a day.
Then who are you in the body ?
I'm her man; she stays alone because I take care of her. I give her money.
I do everything for her; she is my woman.
Who are you in this body ?
She is my woman.
Who are you?
I am the spirit from her mother. It is because she begged me.
Okay, for how long have you stayed inside her ?
She begged me !
10 years now !
She is a sangoma. Did she tell you she is a sangoma ?
She has a shrine house at her mother's place. Did she tell you that ?
She is a sangoma.
She has a shrine?
She went to inyangas for help; non of them - they failed to help her.
What have you done to her ?
Did she tell you that she did abortions ?
She is a sangoma; she used to consult people.
She has a shrine house; she has everything by her mother's house.
Okay ! You spirit, it is time for you to leave this body !
This lady will live !
I will kill the family.
You will not kill the family.
If I'm going out now, I will go to her through one of my friends.
Now you are leaving!
And you will never return to that family in the mighty name of Jesus Christ !
It is time for you to leave this body in the mighty name of Jesus Christ
Out, in the mighty name of Jesus !
You are free.
You are set free through the medium of the New Morning Water in the mighty name of Jesus Christ!
Now rise up. You're free. Rise up and give thanks to God.
Jesus Christ has set you free !
Thank You, Jesus ! Thank You, Lord !
I've waited so many years for this. Thank You. I had to quit my job to come here.
Thank You, Jesus !
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
Emmanuel!
(God with us - Matthew 1:23)
Thank You, Jesus. I'm healed and free !
My name is Refilwe. I'm 34 years old. I'm from South Africa.
The reason that brought me to The SCOAN: It was sangoma spirit - the witch doctor,
which I trained for in 2012.
Ok. So just tell us how you got involved in the issue of becoming a sangome.
What led to you being initiated into this ?
I had a business before. I was running my own saloon business.
Things didn't go well, it got messed up.
So I had to go to a witch doctor for consultation - to tell me what my problem was,
why my business was now failing and why my life was not in order.
After going to the witch doctor for consultation, she told me that I must train to become a sangoma.
That I had a gift in healing people so I must become a sangoma.
I then asked what the procedure was for becoming a sangoma, what had to be done.
He said to me, "Ok, you must give a sacrifice before coming for the training.
You must slaughter a goat
and then you will tell your ancestors that you'll train to become a sangoma.
Then I went to tell my parents that I went to see a witch doctor
because of in my family they didn't worship ancestors.
They used to go to church.
I told them, "The traditional healer told me this is a matter of life and death.
I must do it in order to have money.
And you guys (parents) are going to have money and benefit from this.
So I'm going to heal you. It will benefit the family".
So, they accepted it. I slaughtered a chicken.
Then I begged my ancestors, "This is my offering, I need to go for the training now".
Then I went for my training. I paid money - a lot of money, not a small amount of money.
It cost more than fifty thousand to do the training
because from time to time, you must offer sacrifices, you must slaughter.
All the time you have to offer sacrifices.
During my training, they taught me how to read bones, and how to use charms.
They taught me about different charms like this is for marriage. This is for business. This is for work.
If a person has a problem, struggling to get a job, you must use this charm, so that this person can get a job.
When you graduate, you go to the water.
We went with a goat there. When they slaughter the goat, you must open your mouth.
You drink the goat's blood and then someone will pour it on your body.
And then you talk to the spirit of the water and go inside the water.
There is an underworld secret which not everybody knows about. You go inside the water.
It's a dry land and you sit there.
That's how you receive your things, your bones, your ancestors' clothes, and your beads.
After the water graduation...
Then I went home. When you go home, then you graduate. That's how you become a sangoma.
You are ready to heal people. You are ready to consult people.
People come to you with different types of illnesses, problems in their lives.
So how did you begin to practice as a sangoma after this initiation ?
After your graduation, you'd start to practise.
You burn the essence which will attract people to come to you for consultation.
Then you stow your bones, you read the bones while the people are coming to your shrine.
Okay, sister, we want you to explain very clearly to us.
What you are saying right now - the confession you are giving - is your own personal experience.
You personally went through this initiation process, and began practicing as a sangoma
after you drank the blood of this goat, went into the water to be initiated, to collect the bones and other items
that you'd use to practice and that's how you started work as a sangoma. Is that right?
Yes, that's right. That's correct.
I started training - initiating like consulting people.
Give us an example of how you would go about it when people would approach you?
Okay, people would come to my forefathers' house for consultation.
I would then take them to the shrine house.
Then they would tell me, "My name is so-and-so".
They wouldn't tell me their problem because I had to figure out what their problem was.
I had to throw down the bones and tell them what the problem was,
what brought them there. Then I would tell them, "This is the problem. You are facing this and this".
In order for me to tell them, I had to first talk to my ancestors,
"My ancestors, I have this person so and so. He has come here to consult. Please assist me".
I would hear voices in my ears.
Then they would start to tell me, "Okay, tell the bones that this is the problem of that person.
This is the charm that must be given to that person in order for that person to be okay".
You were practicing this for several years.
You were part and parcel of this - tell us, the people that would come to you with problems,
by the time you actually gave them a charm, what would end up happening to those people?
The charm would not work. People would follow me and tell me that they still had the same problem.
I would tell them, "Ok, come back. Let me take you to the stream, so that you can bathe".
I would consult my ancestors, "The person has phoned me again, the problem is still there.
The problem is not resolved. So what must I do now ?"
They would say, "Take the person to the water so that she can bathe with a chicken.
She must sacrifice a chicken and then things will be fine".
But the problem would still be there for that person. Eventually that person would not come back to me.
Okay, so the people that came to you with problems, after everything, collecting money,
consulting for them, the problem would still continue and even if not, would become worse.
Yes, the problem would still be there for those people who came to me.
You that was practicing as a sangoma, what was happening in your own life at this period?
In my own life I never had peace, my life was falling apart.
I myself needed help.
I would go to other traditional healers, to seek traditional doctors to help myself.
I was busy consulting people, but I myself needed help.
As you worked as a sangoma, what finally happened in the midst of this?
Okay.
I had a dream that they told me that I must go and do training inside the water.
I must go to the ocean. That's how they would lead me inside the water.
I must stay there for two years. Then I would come out as a powerful person.
I told myself, "No, I can't go there. What if I don't come back. I have kids to look after. I have family. I can't".
That's how I decided, "NO! This is not worth it".
I have struggled. I went from one witch doctor to another witch doctor to another - nothing!
Then all that slaughtering of goats, offering sacrifices every time, I had to beg and talk to a goat,
"Goat, please give me money. Goat, please help me. Goat, please I need this".
Every time, month to month, chicken, goat, chicken, goat...
I was tired of that life.
So, people of God, I hope we are listening to our sister's experience.
Especially for those who in the past have visited witch doctors, consulted sangomas.
This person speaking to us now has practical experience as someone that practiced in this,
and at the end of the day realized that everything came to nothing.
Now, sister you are mentioning some of the processes of initiation.
Could you just explain to us with the pictures here, what we are seeing here to verify what you're mentioning.
Okay. Here as you are looking.
This is where I drank the goat blood.
They poured the goat blood on me.
So, that you can accept your ancesters. That you are now officially a witch doctor.
Here, I went to the altar to beg the spirit of water, the mermaid.
Sometimes, these spirits come in different types - crocodile, mermaid or snake.
This is where I went to the water to beg the spirit to help me open my things in the ocean.
This is my shrine house where I practiced as a witch doctor.
This is me here when I did my sangoma dance, wearing this outfit and undergoing my training.
We also want to understand: When you were practicing as a sangoma,
were you also in a relationship with someone or did you get married at this period ?
Yes, I was married. The spirit made me choose between my marriage and them.
So. I had to leave the father of my kids because I was scared.
They said I will die and my family will be in trouble if I don't do this.
So you left your husband to worship these ancestors and to continue your practice as a sangoma?
Yes, I did.
Were you not permitted to have any relationship?
And what was happening to you in your dreams at this period concerning relationships ?
When you are a sangoma, especially when the spirit of a man enters you,
you won't have any feelings for men - only feelings for women.
I never told any of my friends that I was attracted to women.
I would watch women. I would be more attracted to women than men.
Because this spirit did not allow you to have a man in your life, that gave you affection to your fellow females.
Yes, even when I had a man in my life. I wouldn't have feelings for him.
I would never have feelings for that man.
You said it reached a point where you were told that you would have to go underwater
for two years to go through training, to increase your powers as a sangoma.
When you heard this, what step did you take after that ?
I told them, "No, I can't. I'd rather lose everything. I'd rather lose my life.
I can't do it. I'd rather take my life. I can't do it. I'll go to church. I can't do it.
I'm tired of you". I spent more than fifty thousand, hundred thousand,
going from one traditional healer to another. The problem would still be the same.
There was no solution for me.
So after you stopped doing the work of a sangoma, what began to happen to your life?
How did the spirits of sangoma now begin to destroy your life?
After that, I became a heavy smoker. I was a drunkard.
I'd drink from Monday morning until the next day. I'd drink at work, during working hours.
I'd sneak out from work to go drinking and smoking.
My life was going down the drain. There was no (hope).
I didn't have a life. So, I thought my life was over for me.
I'd take 12 or 6 a day - a whole box.
I would smoke - if I didn't smoke, I would shake.
I'd shake hard, "Let me go out to smoke!"
Even when I arrived here in Nigeria, people were looking at me at the airport,
"You are such a beautiful lady but you are smoking".
I was like, "They have to mind their own business. They don't know me.
I smoke. I'm a smoker".
Ok, so you were a chain smoker, a chronic smoker,
and you also took between 6 to 12 bottles of alcohol every day.
Yes
Ok, now. Today, we can see you here in The SCOAN.
Could you just tell us in the midst of this, how did you discover the ministry and what led you to be here today?
I went with my boyfriend to his friend's place. I was so drunk that night.
As we entered that friend's house, on top of the TV, I saw the New Morning Water.
So you saw a bottle of the Morning Water on top of the television of this friend.
Yes.
At this point, did you know anything about the Ministry of Tthe SCOAN,
Prophet T.B. Joshua or the Morning Water?
No, I didn't know anything about them.
When I saw the water, I took the bottle - this friend went to take a shower.
And then I asked myself, "What is this?" I looked at the bottle and kept on asking myself that question.
Then I sprayed myself and put that bottle back on top of the TV.
Then I kept quiet, I remained seated.
You said that at this period, you were completely drunk.
I was completely drunk that night when I saw the New Morning Water.
So, after spraying myself, my boyfriend came back and said,
"Refilwe, you must go home now. It's late". Then I went home.
When I got home and then woke up in the morning, I was like, "Huh? What's going on with my body?"
It was like I was dreaming, like something just went out of me. I was a new person.
I couldn't understand what was going on. I phoned my boyfriend, "Elvis, please I need that water.
I saw that water by your friend's place. Please, where can I get that water? Please!"
He said to me, "Refilwe, you can't get that water. You must go to Nigeria, SCOAN, Emmanuel".
I asked, "Who is Emmanuel? What is SCOAN? What is that?"
He said, "Please, when you have time, you must come and we'll talk. I'll explain everything to you".
So you knew immediately that it was that Morning Water you used
that caused the change in your body when you woke up the following day?
Yes, because the water delivered me.
God didn't judge me when I was drunk. That water delivered me when I was so drunk.
So it was the following morning when you woke up, that they introduced you to the MInistry.
You learned that you can only get this Morning Water here in Nigeria.
So, how did you manage to be here today?
Every day at work, I researched about the Church, passport and visa, and how to get it.
And then I finally made it here,
Okay. Before you made it, what was the last challenge you faced,
especially in your workplace before God enabled you to be here last week?
Okay, the first challenge - there were two roads.
Money or deliverance of my life.
I had to choose between those two roads. Then I prayed to God,
God, I've suffered for many years. This job, this money is nothing to me.
I'd rather quit this job and go for my healing and my deliverance.
I rather take Your road. Money will come after. At this stage, I don't care about money.
My deliverance is more important than money".
So, at your workplace, you were given an ultimatum that either you leave the job or you travel
because you wanted to travel without permission from your job.
So you had to take a critical decision at that moment.
Yes, it was a critical decision because I have bills to pay.
I'm a single parent.
I have kids. I have family (to take care of).
My rent is so expensive. I prayed, "God, You will see me through. I lack no faith.
I trust in You that You will come through for me. I'm quitting this job because I put my trust in You".
Amen, that's how you came straight to The SCOAN.
Now, tell us, sister - can you describe what happened to you last week,
as the evangelists were moving around ministering the New Morning Water.
What happened at that period?
When they were ministering the New Morning Water on me, I was feeling like my intestines were burning.
It was like I was burning inside.
I asked God, "What is going on? I'm burning!"
It was like something just went out of me.
Now I can see the light of God.
Amen! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ !
It's been one week after your wonderful deliverance.
Can you just testify to the changes you've seen in your life?
I thank God, I'm saved.
My life is more important than money. I thank God because He saved me.
I turned in my cigarette packets to one of the workers here,
That was on Monday after the touch from Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Okay, so you mean to say that these were the cigarettes you came with to Nigeria,
because as a chain smoker, you were smoking a packet every day.
Yes.
But after your deliverance, what happened?
After the deliverance on Monday, I handed them to one of the workers here.
So you mean, since last week till today, you have not touched...
No alcohol. No smoking. I'm clean.
And you no longer have that urge?
You said before, that your body would be shaking and desiring to smoke, to drink.
That urge is completely gone now?
Yes, I'd crave. I'd shake if I didn't smoke.
I used to shake when I didn't smoke and drink, but now I don't have that urge anymore.
My body is healed. I'm free, in the mighty name of Jesus!
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ !
So what are you going to do with these cigarettes now?
Throw them away!
It is history! It will never repeat itself!
Amen! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ one more time !
Now, sister, we believe you're in a position to really advise our viewers all over the world.
A lot of people are still having the belief that perhaps if they visited a witch doctor or spiritualist,
they would be helped in one way or another.
But you're here giving your own life experience, testifying to the world that you were once a sangoma.
And every attempt you made to get help yourself failed during that period.
Even the people you thought you were helping actually were only being destroyed.
So what is your word of advice to our viewers?
Especially those who are still patronizing such places?
Ok, my word of advice is to the youth, because spirits are now tormenting the youth.
Especially in my country, and other countries as well. I say to them,
Please, there's no such thing as ancestors. It's only demons that are playing with your mind.
Go to the house of the Lord, to God. At the end, God will come through for you.
As God has come through for me, He will come through for you.
Leave these things, because the end is bad. The sangoma thing brings poverty, death in the family,
misery, and pain. Please! I advise especially the youth,
Don't be fooled by these traditional healers, witch doctors.
Stick to the Word of God because Jesus is alive !
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Testimony continues
My name is Refilwe. I'm 34 years old. I'm from South Africa.
The reason that brought me to The SCOAN was that I was suffering from the spirit of sangoma.
God finally came through for me. I managed to come to The SCOAN to get my deliverance and healing.
After all these years I had suffered from these spirits, I thank Lord Jesus because He came through for me.
Today I'm here, and I'm grateful to God, for what He has done for me.
After my deliverance, I can feel a lot of changes in my body.
As I have mentioned in my testimony , the worst of all was that I had to quit my job
because the deliverance in my life was more important than money.
God has already given me another position. I got another job, and I can't wait to go home,
to start a new life and start a new job.
You mean after you gave your testimony, you actually received employment in another position?
After you lost your job to come here, you now have another job ?
Yes, I now have another job. God has given me a better job.
It's with a company that I've been praying for all these months to work for.
So now I've gotten that opportunity from God.
I'm going to return to my country to start my new life, my new job.
In a couple of months, I'm going to open my new business.
Thank You, Jesus Christ !
And all of that - your past life, the spirit of smoking, drinking, everything is gone.
I don't have that craving anymore. Everything just disappeared. I'm a new person now.
I'm ready to kick in - in life.
Thank You, Jesus. We thank God for your life, sister.
And we're here today with a message for you from Prophet T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV partners.
The man of God said he wants to really support you, as you are going back to start your new life now.
We know you really went through a test of faith before coming here to The SCOAN.
You persevered, you overcame and today your life is a living testimony
So Prophet T.B. Joshua said he wants to support you with this gift of 1,000 US dollars.
It is from Emmanuel TV partners and the prophet for you to really get going in your new life in Christ Jesus.
I am so happy. God has done it again. I thank you, Man of God, for the second gift.
The first gift was that you brought me inside the church, gave me free food and free accommodation.
I thank you for that. May the Lord bless you in the name of Jesus !
I thank you. And now this money! You saw that this lady (me) needed this money.
I thank you, Man of God. I thank you. May the Lord continue to bless you !
I thank you so much. I thank you.
Hallelujah. Thank You, Jesus Christ, once again.
We can see our sister overcome with joy at this wonderful blessing she's received.
This is 1,000 US dollars and the Word of God - The Mirror.
What can you say, sister?
I am so excited!
I didn't expect this !
I thank God. I thank You, Lord. I trusted in you.
That's why I had strong faith before I came here.
I said, "God, I know You'll never fail me. I know You'll never let me down".
I trusted in You from the minute I entered that plane. I thank You, Lord Jesus. Thank You so much !
Hallelujah ! Wow, indeed a million thanks are not enough.
Finally, sister, what is your word of advice to our viewers ?
My word of advice today is especially to the youngsters.
The witch doctor training things, the sangoma training things, they target mostly the youngsters.
There is no such thing as sangoma, ancestors - they are just demons.
They are just demons that will eat your money. They will finish your money.
Once they're done with you, they are through with you, then you'll become nothing.
I've learned that. I've been there. I have accepted Jesus now.
So, I want the youngsters to please follow the Word of God.
The Word of God takes you to the end.
The world of ancestors is just a meantime life.
Once they are through with you, you'll never be the same again. Thank You. Lord Jesus Christ !
We thank God for that word of advice. It is really born of life experience from our sister today.
She is victorious in Christ and her past is over and we give all the glory to God.
We believe she'll be coming back very soon with even more wonderful testimonies to share,
and we want to encourage you to continue to go forth, make the Word of God the standard for your life
and we believe the best is yet to come in Jesus' name !
Amen. I thank You, Lord Jesus !
Thank You for healing me. Thank You for everything You have done for me !